Christi Weir

UX/UI Designer Pittsburgh PA

Contact

weir.christi@gmail.com

Portfolio | LinkedIn

Education

Certification, UI/UX Design Career Foundry, 2020-2021

M.S. Business Administration Southern NH Univ., 2016-2018

B.A. Psychology

Penn. State Univ., 2008-2012

Skills & Tools

 ${\sf Sketch}$

Figma
Adobe Suite

HTML

HIMI

CSS

User Research

Project Strategy

Prototyping

User Testing

Visual Design

User Flows

Visual Design

Style Guides

Profile

UX/UI designer with a background in psychology and business administration. Experienced in creative-problem solving and communication. On a mission to bring empathy and a user-centered focus to design to improve the lives of people through technology.

Experience

Freight Forwarder

DSV Air & Sea (Formerly Panalpina) | March 2018 - Present

- Managed global and local accounts, using problem solving to ensure consistent level of service for clients. Utilized extensive knowledge of US customs regulations, trade policy, and company initiatives to meet the client's needs, leading to continued business partnerships.
- Consistently maximized profits on every shipment by negotiating rates with vendors, seeking most cost-effective trade lanes, and coordinating with overseas colleagues to ensure timely departures of cargo.

Customer Service

Smith Transport | June 2016 - March 2018

- Spearheaded implementation of new supply chain processes that contributed to the success of high-revenue peak season business with Amazon
- Maintained consistent customer service outside of business hours, utilizing a wide range of knowledge of specific accounts, driver management, and US Department of Transportation regulations.

Financial Service Associate

First Commonwealth Bank | July 2015 - June 2016

- Built strong relationships with customers through the use of active listening to tailor my advice to their individual needs increasing customer satisfaction
- Navigated multiple cross departmental systems to effectively execute customer sales with a high degree of accuracy

Head Server/Certified Trainer

Outback Steakhouse | July 2012 - October 2016

- Facilitated the establishment of a consistent company culture in employees through proper training and delivery of company procedures
- Motivated employees during one-on-one sessions identifying areas of success and opportunity leading to improved overall performance

Therapeutic Staff Support

Alternative Community Resource Program | August 2012 - July 2016

- Provided support to behavioral services counselors to monitor and ensure success of client's treatment plan.
- Conducted outreach activities for parents in the school community to increase knowledge surrounding mental health issues and connected students with additional support services in the community